<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on harre.dev</title>
    <link>https://harre.dev/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on harre.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© harre.dev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harre.dev/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - The 10 minute build</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and I discuss the concept of the 10-minute build, emphasizing its importance in maintaining developer focus and efficiency.
We explore the technical and cultural aspects of build processes, the significance of team dynamics, and the necessity of standardizing builds across different teams. The conversation also touches on the balance between speed and reliability in software deployment, advocating for a culture of confidence in shipping software quickly while minimizing risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - Product Mindset</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</guid>
      <description>A new episode launched on the Cloud Native Chronicles podcast and we&amp;rsquo;re talking about Product Mindset. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit all over the place with this one but I think the main message is clear: Think about what you want to build and for who.
In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and Sander explore the concept of a product mindset in software development.
They discuss the differences between building software and creating a product, emphasizing the importance of understanding stakeholder needs and engaging with them throughout the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - Balanced teams</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-balanced-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-balanced-teams/</guid>
      <description>The first episode is out! Johan and I talk about balanced teams.
In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and Sander discuss the concept of balanced teams in cloud-native development. They explore the essential roles needed for effective product development, the risks associated with not validating products, and the challenges posed by siloed organizations.
The conversation emphasizes the importance of collaboration across disciplines and the need for leadership to drive cultural change within organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first podcast appearance</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/capicast-podcast-devex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/capicast-podcast-devex/</guid>
      <description>On the 9th of August 2022 Robert Kloosterhuis and myself recorded a podcast episode with the nice folks at CodeCapi. They invited us over to talk about developer experience. A pretty broad topic and we covered a lot of stuff in the recording.
This was my first experience with recording something so I was a bit nervous but in the end it was a great experience and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the episode that came from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
