<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://harre.dev/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>harre.dev</title>
    <link>https://harre.dev/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://harre.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ramblings from a guy writing code and other stuff.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing pointer size in Jetbrains IDEs on Pop OS</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/pop-24-04-jetbrains/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a fun one to start the holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After upgrading to Pop OS 24.04 I had a nasty case of inconsistent pointers.
Specifically when using any of the Jetbrains IDEs (PyCharm, DataGrip, Rider, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving the pointer onto ANY of the IDEs would blow up the cursor to a comical size.
Probably something to do with how scaling (does not?) work properly for some stuff when the whole Wayland vs X11 thing crops up on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harre.dev/blog/pop-24-04-jetbrains/pic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Looking good there Mr. Pointer&quot;&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Took a picture because screenshotting your pointer is hard...&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Linux foo is not good enough to fully explain why any of this is happening (something with Java, X and Wayland fighting), but you can set properties for the stuff that is depending on X using a file in your home directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new file called &lt;code&gt;.Xresources&lt;/code&gt; in your home directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the file (nano, VSCode, whatever) and add the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-ini&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ini&quot;&gt;Xcursor.theme: DMZ-White
Xcursor.size: 24&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, apply the new settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;xrdb .Xresources&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reboot to make sure everything picks up on the new settings and your pointer should now look right again when using Jetbrains IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/pop-24-04-jetbrains/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Python and UV with Docker</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/python-uv-docker/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Using Python and UV with Docker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick little recipe here that I ended up piecing together last night.
I had set up a new Python &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastapi.tiangolo.com/&quot;&gt;FastAPI&lt;/a&gt; project using &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.astral.sh/uv/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and needed a container image for the project as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the regular Python image as a base and then including the &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; bits to get access to &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;s functionality.
Then copying my files and syncing the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then proceeded to use the regular FastAPI commands for the final &lt;code&gt;CMD&lt;/code&gt; instruction to run the project when the container is started but no dice, it kept saying that &lt;code&gt;fastapi&lt;/code&gt; was not a thing you can run. The key is to also invoke &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; in the startup process since &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; is managing the environment that has all the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the full &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; I ended up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-docker&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-docker&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; python:3.13-slim-trixie&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;ENV&lt;/span&gt; UV_SYSTEM_PYTHON=1&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token options&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;ghcr.io/astral-sh/uv:latest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; /uv /uvx /bin/&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;WORKDIR&lt;/span&gt; /app&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt; uv.lock pyproject.toml /app/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;RUN&lt;/span&gt; uv sync --locked&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt; . /app/&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;EXPOSE&lt;/span&gt; 8080&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token instruction&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;CMD&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;uv&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;run&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;fastapi&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;run&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;main.py&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;--port&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;8080&quot;&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a short search, but still, here for later use and so you don&#39;t have to look any further!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/python-uv-docker/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infinite innovation</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/infinite-innovation/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Infinite innovation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have an nice platform, onboarding experience is great, developer experience spot on. Teams are all self-sufficient and driving their own ideas and products and all is well in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day, a team comes up and says: &amp;quot;Where can I bring our apps that we want to have managed by someone else?&amp;quot;. The question that then comes is &amp;quot;What do you mean &#39;managed&#39;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://harre.dev/blog/you-build-it-you-run-it/&quot;&gt;You build it, you run it&lt;/a&gt;, right?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little digging then brings up that the team in question has built every idea they thought was valuable into an app and are now so busy keeping everything up and running that they are stuck on a maintenance treadmill for all the stuff they made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big hypothetical example but one I&#39;ve seen happen and for which the solution is... complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should &amp;quot;you build it, you run it&amp;quot; take a backseat and let teams offload their work so that they can build more stuff? Or... maybe the teams should not be able to keep building to the point they go beyond their ability to handle it all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option 1: Set up a facility/team that will serve as a harbor for the apps (that essentially are being left beind by their owners).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option 2: The teams with these large portfolios should grow to meet their new demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either option will probably work but is costly no matter how you spin it. I guess there&#39;s an option 3, which is downsizing the workload for the team by culling the amount of stuff. Bring down apps that provide little value. That will involve evaluating everything and then finding a way to make decisions. Assuming that the team worked in good faith, might be very hard because everything has a purpose and is used by a bunch of end-users that depend on the provided solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point I&#39;m trying to put to words is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can teams in an organization (assuming they are all self-organizing) expland the portfolio as the see fit? I think there should be some alignment and maybe even some gatekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research must go in to any new idea to check if it is something to invest time and energy in. Does this thing we want to build already exist in some way? Can this thing we want be included in something that has similar features? Is this even needed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From experience...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A road I&#39;ve traveled involved setting up a way of finding what is actually running on the platform, and who the owners are. Once my team and I had a clear picture, work started to see how healthy the whole thing was. Some basic checks against the portfolio were introduced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When was this last deployed? (where anything over 90 days ago got a fail)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this running on an up-to-date stack?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this using the latest build tooling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of these can be either green or red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First results we&#39;re at best &amp;quot;Oh-kay.&amp;quot;, many apps were not meeting the basic criteria we set which meant that they had not had any attention in quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step in the process is getting in touch with teams and notifying them on the state of their portfolio. To make life a bit easier, some tooling when along side this to automate some of the work like a dashboard where teams can check for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new wisdom, we asked teams to investigate and update their stuff to ensure they got green marks. Slowly but surely the board became more green and, even better, a lot of stuff was removed from the platform altogether!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not easy, and as with anything involving asking others to do something that might not align with their own goals, critisism was aplenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nothing for free&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extension of the expidition we&#39;re on to run a tighter ship is everyone&#39;s favorite topic: cost calculation. On-prem, public cloud, hybrid, nothing is ever free. The public cloud makes this easy, pay up, or no compute. On-prem is more complicated but if you have a good view of the portfolio and you can link that to consumed resources, you can run that through a calculation to (roughly) find out what each app costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of a ramble this whole thing but I felt that I should write it down so here we are. Should teams be able to keep building without limits? Probably not, but there should be &lt;a href=&quot;https://harre.dev/blog/are-you-failing-enough/&quot;&gt;freedom to experiment and try new things&lt;/a&gt;. Don&#39;t lock things down to tight or the shadow IT monster will start invading your organization again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/infinite-innovation/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting my airconditioning system free</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/setting-acs-free/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smartlight.me/smart-home-devices/wifi-devices/wifi-dongle-air-conditioners-midea-idea-electrolux-for-home-assistant&quot;&gt;SLWF01-Pro&lt;/a&gt; works great with Midea Xtreme Save Pro airconditioning units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setting my airconditioning system free&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that long ago on a hot sweaty day I pulled the trigger to have airconditioning installed in my house. After a short round of finding the right folks for the job and waiting a few weeks it was finally done. Work from home would now be comfy every day of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When selecting the units I asked about automation but the installers didn&#39;t really know beyond &amp;quot;yes it has WiFi and there&#39;s an app&amp;quot;, which meant that there was at least some way of doing things remotely. The units we ended up getting are made by Midea (the Xtreme Save Pro model), which to my knowledge is one of the biggest manufacturerers of these units in the world so the chances of something already existing out there were pretty high as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation everything work as expected and it was time to set up the WiFi and app. The setup procedure was straightforward with QR-codes but the app, while functional, was extremely laggy and of course it had a dependency on some cloud system of questionable reliability... It put up with it for a little while but deep down a voice kept saying that there must be a better way...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ESPHome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some searching around in the Home Assistant forums led me to a product called &lt;strong&gt;SLWF01-Pro&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a universal controller for airconditioning units. To my great surprise, most of these AC units use the same control language and some smart folks ended up making a USB-device that talks this language AND is compatible with ESPHome! I already had ESPHome up and running for some other stuff so this would be amazing if it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small problem... There wasn&#39;t really any conclusive evidence of my specific units also being compatible. There was a good chance but a single post on a forum saying works is not a lot to go on. After some consideration and more reading on the crazy list of compatible units I bought some a few of these SLWF01-Pro devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works flawlessly! Setup was easy through WiFi, Each unit immidiately popped up in the ESPHome integration in Home Assistant and all the bells and whistles work. You can even disable the annoying &lt;em&gt;beep&lt;/em&gt; the unit makes when you send a command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the thing I was really after, I can automate the operation of these units using Home Assitant based any number of metrics such humidity, electricity price, temperature, time, whatever I can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Free at last&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more cloud, works offline as long as my own network stays up. No more questionable app or wifi dongles that report who-knows-what to who-knows-where and one extra feature to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/setting-acs-free/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No more analytics</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/no-more-analytics/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;No more analytics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve decided to remove all analytics tracking from my website. The data has no meaningful purpose for me (I&#39;m not pulling in any crazy numbers of traffic to begin with) and the writing is something I do when I feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fairanalytics.de/&quot;&gt;fairanalytics.de&lt;/a&gt; for their privacy-first stance on how analytics should be done. Highly recommended you check them out if you are looking for a privacy friendly analytics solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/no-more-analytics/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Cloud Native Chronicles episodes</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-tdd-xp/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;New Cloud Native Chronicles episodes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New episodes dropped recently and I totally forgot to post them here! Now I could create a post for each of them but nah, here you go :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Golden paths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&quot;embed-iframe&quot; style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/5zbvylSpdW7CEPL3Gk9Dx6/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Platform as a product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&quot;embed-iframe&quot; style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/2GcoZqZrHUVLk7FQJY8I0w/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&quot;embed-iframe&quot; style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/43wz0gbrIVHK1L85VOrE0B/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Test-driven development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&quot;embed-iframe&quot; style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/0adgKgY2rxQY3l00Oh5zwm/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-tdd-xp/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The post about AI</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/the-post-about-ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;The post about AI&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lets clamp that down right away, this is more about LLMs, and even more specificically, code generation using LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub CoPilot, Cursor, ChatGPT, you name it, it&#39;s everywhere in developer land. I&#39;ve been using Github CoPilot (in the browser for now) to have it do some work for a while now and it&#39;s been hit-and-miss. It&#39;ll do the boilerplate stuff well enough but at the same time it&#39;s very easy get served something that makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current workflow is roughly like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; specific and explicit in what you want done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read through the generated thing at least once fully and make sure I understand what the code will do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on refinements/improvements (this is almost a given for every attempt) and changes for things I don&#39;t need or are just plain wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for verification by means of tests that go with the previously generated thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I&#39;m usually happy with whatever was created and will integrate the generated code by hand into the final product, validating once more that whatever I&#39;m integrating is actually the thing I want. I&#39;m not yet convinced that whatever was generated can right go into the product I&#39;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For hobby stuff and exploratory coding for ideas I generally let the LLM go wild and use whatever it brings. Speed and discovery at the cost of validation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s more to explore here though, but I am no authority to make any calls on where this LLM trend will go. It might still improve a lot, or maybe we&#39;re stalling out... I have no idea, but here goes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Software... reviewer?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve been seeing articles from folks letting the LLM do all the work of fixing the bugs and writing the features. It sounds like living on the edge to me, but if it works it works. With enough validation, why not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about the developer prompting their way to a working product? Are they still a &amp;quot;software developer&amp;quot;? Or is that what a &amp;quot;prompt engineer&amp;quot; (LMAO) is? It sounds more like &amp;quot;software reviewer&amp;quot; when the AI is doing all the work and the human in the loop is just there as a safeguard, only reviewing the outputs. That does not sound like a fun job to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vibe coding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess an extension of &amp;quot;the AI does all the work&amp;quot;, is just going with whatever is given by the LLM and trying to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned already, I do this a lot for exploration, experimentation and hobby stuff. It&#39;s for me only and I&#39;m the only user. Vibe coding my way into any substantial production grade product sounds irresponsible to me. Maybe when we see more improvments in the models that are used for code generation but I feel this is flying way to close to the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect to this is that if you do find a bug or problem in the code and fix it, how do you prevent the LLM from making the same mistake again? If this was a human at work there would be the possibility for learning and experience but the LLM is static. Can you prompt the problem away for the next run? Update (or change) the model? Sounds a bit problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The AI-native developer??&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve seen this one come by a few times as well recently and I really don&#39;t know where to go with this. One explanation says that this type of role (?) is using AI throughout the whole development lifecycle, but then we&#39;re still generating code, docs, a pipeline, that&#39;s not much different from what most LLM use looks like I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another take I&#39;ve seen is that the prompts used to create the product are the source of truth and not the code. This sounds a lot like vibe coding on steroids. I would love to see this in practice for anything substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The ladder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One concern I see is that while we can ramp up the productivity by generating more code, being able to review code will become more important, but the ability to review code requires experience. If there&#39;s no path to gain that experience through actual hands-on coding (because the LLM is doing all that work), how is a junior going to pick up the skills and experience to judge the output of an LLM? Where do seniors come from when there is no good way to gain practical experience and skills as a junior?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running code you didn&#39;t write and might not fully understand from a source that can confidently make mistakes and/or make stuff up... I guess you can see where this is going. Dependencies you didn&#39;t vet that are suggested by that same source? Nah...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Anyway...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole LLM thing is another (pretty great) tool in the toolbox. I still use regular web search for stuff but when it&#39;s something code related I generally go straight for the LLM and write out the question and ask for a sample to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web search will sometimes follow up a piece of generated code when there&#39;s some halucinated non-existing crap in the sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t expect the use of these tools to go away, in their current state they&#39;re great for boilerplate stuff and cranking out an idea in a very short time. If LLMs have peaked or not, I don&#39;t know but it&#39;s here to stay. Getting familiar with them and how to best use them will only add to your available tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just some thoughts and questions that came to me when I was off on vacation for two weeks. No real answers, more questions, thank you for reading :smile:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/the-post-about-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - The 10 minute build</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Cloud Native Chronicles - The 10 minute build&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and I discuss the concept of the 10-minute build, emphasizing its importance in maintaining developer focus and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explore the technical and cultural aspects of build processes, the significance of team dynamics, and the necessity of standardizing builds across different teams.
The conversation also touches on the balance between speed and reliability in software deployment, advocating for a culture of confidence in shipping software quickly while minimizing risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/6XphnYj8MECxflX0lqDs3c/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal Tracker alternatives</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/pitoval-tracker-alternatives/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Pivotal Tracker alternatives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pivotal Tracker is an application designed to help teams manage their projects using agile methodologies.
It allows users to create and prioritize stories, tasks, and epics, and collaborate in real-time with other developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, Pivotal Tracker is being shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bye-tracker.net/&quot;&gt;linked site&lt;/a&gt; shows teams that are working hard to build the next iteration of this tool to allow teams to collaborate around a shared backlog of stories in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://bye-tracker.net/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/pitoval-tracker-alternatives/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - Product Mindset</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Cloud Native Chronicles - Product Mindset&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new episode launched on the Cloud Native Chronicles podcast and we&#39;re talking about Product Mindset.
We&#39;re a bit all over the place with this one but I think the main message is clear: Think about what you want to build and for who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and Sander explore the concept of a product mindset in software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They discuss the differences between building software and creating a product, emphasizing the importance of understanding stakeholder needs and engaging with them throughout the development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation highlights the significance of early feedback, iterative planning, and team collaboration, using Tesla as a case study to illustrate successful product development strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The episode concludes with key takeaways on starting small and fostering a cultural shift towards agile methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/2snFo9vBKPjv9kCCZQUaqX/video?utm_source=generator&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - Balanced teams</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-balanced-teams/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Cloud Native Chronicles - Balanced teams&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first episode is out! Johan and I talk about balanced teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and Sander discuss the concept of balanced teams in cloud-native development.
They explore the essential roles needed for effective product development, the risks associated with not validating products, and the challenges posed by siloed organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation emphasizes the importance of collaboration across disciplines and the need for leadership to drive cultural change within organizations.
Key takeaways include the necessity of diverse skill sets in teams and the dangers of building products without user validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border-radius:12px&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/0OxImLIsqO4G2lbQAKJTKY/video?utm_source=generator&amp;t=0&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/cloud-native-chronicles-balanced-teams/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to a Self Managed Life by FUTO</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/futo-self-managed-life/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Introduction to a Self Managed Life by FUTO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guide to building your own sovereign cloud, from top to bottom. Everything you could self-manage is probably in here. Amazing content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://wiki.futo.org/wiki/Introduction_to_a_Self_Managed_Life:&lt;em&gt;a_13_hour&lt;/em&gt;%26_28_minute_presentation_by_FUTO_software&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/futo-self-managed-life/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Simple System Now by Dan North</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/best-simple-system-now/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Best Simple System Now by Dan North&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long-form post about focussing on the simplest system you can get away with &lt;strong&gt;right now&lt;/strong&gt;.
I like the idea but I bet it takes quite some discipline to not accidentally over or under-do the thing you are looking to ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We can do this the quick way and pay later, or the thorough way and pay now.&amp;quot; This seems to be a fundamental dichotomy in software development, between ‘perfectionism’ and ‘pragmatism’, but I do not think it has to be a trade-off at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Best Simple System for Now is the simplest system that meets the needs of the product right now, written to an appropriate standard. It has no extraneous or over-engineered code, and any code it does have is exactly as robust and reliable as it needs to be, neither more nor less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan North&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://dannorth.net/best-simple-system-for-now/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/best-simple-system-now/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest &amp; Desert by Beth Andres-Beck</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/forest-and-desert/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Forest &amp;amp; Desert by Beth Andres-Beck&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article describes two distinct cultures that exist for software development. The forest and the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a path from the desert to the forest, a series of small, safe steps a community can take to terraform the landscape. No developer can do it alone, and no amount of technology will get us there, but it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beth Andres-Beck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://tidyfirst.substack.com/p/forest-and-desert&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/forest-and-desert/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team priorities</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/team-priorities/</link>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Team priorities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all work is equally important in the stream of stuff that needs to get done when building and shipping software. So how do you make sense of what to work on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If work items are prioritized outside your development team, you need to have a discussion about ownership. A team that does not have control over what to work on is not in a position of ownership and (assuming the team is working in good faith) cannot be held responsible for any misaligned outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the team is in control over what work that needs doing. How do you then ensure that whatever goes to the top of the list is the most important thing to work on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every change you make to your software should have a desirable impact on some metric. Could be usability, speed, cost, flexibility or some other measure. If the proposed change doesn&#39;t really move any needles in any way, it should probably make way for something that does!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice there will be more factors at play such as changes requested by the organization itself versus changes requested by end-users or maybe other stakeholders and the team can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://harre.dev/blog/team-priorities/false&quot;&gt;innovate and experiment by themselves&lt;/a&gt;. A balance must be found to keep make sure the most impactful changes get developed. If you ignore your end-users, satisfaction will drop and people will stop using your product to find something that does work. Ignoring the business will probably result in your team losing funding, disbanded or shut down in some other way for not aligning with the goals of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be up to the team to figure out how to maintain that balance. Getting feedback early and often helps a lot in ensuring you are still &amp;quot;building the right thing, at the right time&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep important stakeholders in the loop of your plans and priorities and all that&#39;s left is figuring out &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; to actually build the things that make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting the development teams in charge is probably a huge shift for many organizations but stepping away from &amp;quot;feature-factories&amp;quot; (where teams are fed a stream of changes to implement without context or feedback loops) will greatly improve the sense of ownership and responsibility for the members of the teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harre.dev/blog/team-priorities/balanced-teams.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Balanced Team&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some great resources on getting to this new way of structuring teams and way of working can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtopologies.com/&quot;&gt;Team Topologies book&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://labspractices.com/learningpaths/application-development/balanced-teams/&quot;&gt;Balanced Teams approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sander Harrewijnen</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/team-priorities/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>