<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on harre.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on harre.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>sharrewijnen@live.com (Sander Harrewijnen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sharrewijnen@live.com (Sander Harrewijnen)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© harre.dev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paved road - Templates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/paved-load-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sharrewijnen@live.com (Sander Harrewijnen)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/paved-load-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous post about paving the road to production there were some ideas around offering deployment pipelines as a service in your organization. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;re going to take it up a level and have a look what we can do to remove even more friction, specifically when creating a new app from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The process of creating a new app generally looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pick runtime and language&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pick any suitable frameworks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add any additional dependencies for stuff like databases, single sign on, logging, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrate all the above&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure it all works locally&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up configs for various environments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up a pipeline&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deploy to dev/test or other environment to get pipeline working&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create value for your users ✨&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you go ahead and start building something generic that you can quickly duplicate for new apps, you should think about what you are willing to support and what level of customization is going to make the most sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paved road - Deployments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/paved-load-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sharrewijnen@live.com (Sander Harrewijnen)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/paved-load-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speeding up developer teams by eliminating waste and busywork can come in many forms. A huge step comes through automation, deployment specifically. Getting your app to production in an automated manner through some sort of pipeline is a huge timesaver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given this automation, you can take it one step further by moving the creation and management of those pipelines one step up and offer ready made pipelines that teams can take from the digital shelf. These pipelines can be managed by the internal developer community or maybe a supporting team that already enables teams in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
