<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chronicles on harre.dev</title>
    <link>https://harre.dev/tags/chronicles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chronicles on harre.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© harre.dev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harre.dev/tags/chronicles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - The 10 minute build</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-10-minute-build/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and I discuss the concept of the 10-minute build, emphasizing its importance in maintaining developer focus and efficiency.
We explore the technical and cultural aspects of build processes, the significance of team dynamics, and the necessity of standardizing builds across different teams. The conversation also touches on the balance between speed and reliability in software deployment, advocating for a culture of confidence in shipping software quickly while minimizing risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Chronicles - Product Mindset</title>
      <link>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harre.dev/blog/chronicles-product-mindset/</guid>
      <description>A new episode launched on the Cloud Native Chronicles podcast and we&amp;rsquo;re talking about Product Mindset. We&amp;rsquo;re a bit all over the place with this one but I think the main message is clear: Think about what you want to build and for who.
In this episode of Cloud Native Chronicles, hosts Johan and Sander explore the concept of a product mindset in software development.
They discuss the differences between building software and creating a product, emphasizing the importance of understanding stakeholder needs and engaging with them throughout the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
